A Guide to the George E. Uhlenbeck papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA125
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1958-1981; 3; 2 Cubic Feet
  - Max Planck Medaille-Deutsche Phys. Gesellschaft, Düsseldorf, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1961-1963 July (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences August, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences-Minutes, Laws and By-Laws, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - National Academy of Sciences-Minutes, Laws and By-Laws, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - National Science Foundation-Project Referee Reports, 1960 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - National Science Foundation-Project Referee Reports, 1966-1973 1975 1977 1981 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 'The Natural Philosopher', 1962 1965 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Nordisk Institut for Teoretisk Atomfysik (NORDITA), 1964 1967 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Optical Society of America, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Phillips Research Laboratories Reprint List, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Prentice-Hall Inc., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Rockefeller Institute-Requests for Appointments to the Faculty, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - 'Science' - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Science and Technology, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - John T. Tate Committee, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Verenigung van Wis. en Natuurkundige Studenten Voor-Candidaten A-E, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Wheeler Committee, 1962-1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The Wheeler Committee, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - John Wiley & Sons. Inc.-Interscience Publishers, 1962 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Zuiver Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek (Z. O. E.) (Netherlands Organization for the Advancement of Pure Research), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Manuscripts, Speeches, Seminars, Lecture Notes, 1963-1980, undated; 4; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Includes: Lectures in Statistical Mechanics, Introduction to the General Theory of Relativity and An Outline of Statistical Mechanics.
  - Mss. Alte und Neue Fragen der Statistischen Mechanik (in English) Speech at the Conference of the German Physical Society, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Mss. A. P. S. Meeting. Speech on S. A. Guidsmit's Recent Death, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mss. Book Reviews: The Image of Eternity: Roots of Time in the Physical World, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mss. The Classical Theory of the Critical Phenomena. Conference on Phenomena in the Neighborhood of Critical Points, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mss. The Macroscopic Causality Problem, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Is There A Direction In Time?" National Academy of Science, Seattle (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mss. On the Origin of the Quantized Vortex Lines in Superficial Helium, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Mss. On the Van Der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion of the Distribution Functions. With P.C. Hemmer and M. Kac, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Mss. On the Van Der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion of the Critical Region. With P.C. Hemmer and M. Kac, 1963 1964 undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Mss. An Outline of Statistical Mechanics. Lecture-Noordwyck-Summer, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mss. Some Notes on the Relation Between Fluid Mechanics and Statistical Physics for the Annual Review of Fluid Mechanics, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Some Problems in the Kinetic Theory of Dilute Gases. Given at the Sydney Chapman Memorial Lecture, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Mss. Some Questions in Statistical Mechanics. The T. H. Berlin Memorial Lecture, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Summarizing Remarks - The N.U.P.A.P. Conference on Statistical Mechanics, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Mss. SUNY-Symposium on the Future of Biology, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 'Van Der Waals Revisited' Universiteit von Amsterdam, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Notebooks, 1920-197?, undated; 5; 2.8 Cubic Feet
  Arranged in chronological order with undated items arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Brandeis Summer Institute in Theoretical Physics, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Fundamental Problems in Statistical Mechanics, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Lectures delivered at the Centro de Estudios Avanzados del Instituto Politécnico National. Mexico.
  - Introduction to the General Theory of Relativity-Aero 595-695, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Lectures 1 thru 10.
  - Introduction to the General Theory of Relativity-Aero 595-695, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Lectures 11 thru 21.
  - Lectures-Laws of Thermodynamics (1 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Lectures-Untitled (first page missing 2 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Lectures-Notes on the Theory of Phase Transitions (3 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Lectures-Notes: Distribution of Average with Poisson Distribution (4 of 14) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Lectures-The Spherical Mode for Ferromagnetism (5 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Lectures-Lectures in Quantum Statistical Mechanics (6 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Lectures-Untitled. (7of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Lectures-Untitled. (8 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Lectures-Ch. 2. The Kinetic Method of Bolzmann (9 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Lectures-Ch. 6. The Problem of Bolzmann (10 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Lectures-Ch. 7. The Kinetic Method of Bolzmann (11 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Lectures-Ch. 8. The Statistical Method of Bolzmann (12 of 14) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Lectures-Ch. 8. The Statistical Method of Bolzmann (13 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lectures-Ch. 9. The Ideas of Gibbs (14 of 14), undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Lectures in Statistical Mechanics, 1961-1963 1966 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    [For book contract with The American Mathematical Society].
  - Thermodynamics/Statistical Theory. Quantum Mechanics Seminars, 1962-1965 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - University of Colorado, 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Uhlenbeck Reprints, 1925-1980, undated; 6; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Problem v. Durchlit Existentieren-College Droste [English/Dutch], 1920-1921 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - E. Schrodinger-Zur Einsteinische Gastheorie [in Dutch], 1926 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Maxwell-Theory I., 1927 February (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Maxwell-Theory II, 1927 2nd Semester-1928 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Aanteekeiningen I. Ann Arbor [Dutch/English], 1928-1930 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Statistical Mechanics I., 1928 January-June (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Statistical Mechanics II. [English/Dutch], undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Statistical Mechanics III. [in Dutch], undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Partial Differential Equations. I (Till Christmas 1928), 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Partial Differential Equations. II (After Christmas 1928), 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Partial Differential Equations. III, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Quantum Electrodynamics. G. E. Uhlenbeck. 1929-30, 2nd Semester, 1929-1930, 2nd Semester (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Fluctuation Theorie, Brownian Motion etc. Summer, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Mechanics IV. Ann Arbor, After '30. Utrecht' 35. [English/Dutch], 1930-1935 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Ordinary Diff. Equations. N. D. (early thirties) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Positron Calculation Quantum Theory Summer, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Untitled-II. Ann Arbor-Utrecht. [English/Dutch/German], 1934-1938 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Untitled. [Notes-in Dutch], 1935-1939 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Nucleiana - College. [in Dutch], 1935-1936 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Dirac Theorie. [in Dutch], 1937-1938 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Electronen en Relativiteitstheorie. [in Dutch], 1937-1938 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Mechanica. [in Dutch], 1937-1938 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Utrecht and Notes for Lectures in Ann Arbor Summer School. [Dutch/English], 1938 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Cosmic Rays-II. Utrecht and Ann Arbor. [Dutch/English], 1939 January 24 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - IV-Nuclear Physics-Field Theories. Internal Conversion, 1939 September 20 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Ming Chen Wang [notes]. 'Must be 40s', 1940s (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Statistical Low Temperature Physics VI, 1940 March 28 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Physics VII, Mesomia Elem. Particles. [English/Dutch]. March 1941 (up to '56), 1941 March (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Statistics-Hydrodynamics VIII Esp. Turbulence of Noise, 1942 January; 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Statistics-Hydrodynamics VIII Esp. Turbulence of Noise, 1942 January; 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hydrodynamics, Compr. Fluids IX, Electro Magn. Theory, 1942 March (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Statistics-Viral Coefficient, etc., Transport Phenom., Graphs. Dec. (19) 42, 1942 December (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Solids XI, 1943 March (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Non-linear Vibrations XI B. Rad. Lab, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bogoluboy's Theory Plasma XII-Stat. Mechanics, 1944 December (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - XVII-Superfluids I-Statistics Superconduct.; Superfluidity, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Field Theories XIII B, Princeton, 1948 October (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Field Theories XIV, Princeton, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Statistical Mechanics-Lecture Notes. I, [circa 1950-1960] (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Statistical Mechanics-Lecture Notes. II, [circa 1950-1960] (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Statistical Mechanics-XV. Transport Phen., H-Theorem, Engodic Theorem. Apr. (19) 52, 1952 April (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Group Theory I, [circa 1952] (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Group Theory II, Fall 1952 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Graphs, Combinations. XVI, 1953 May (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Theory of Relativity I, Lecture Notes, 1953-1954 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Theory of Relativity II, Lecture Notes, 1953-1954 1955-1956 1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Mechanics Esp. Many Hazy Problems. XIII, 1954 October (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Particles XVIII, Fall 1958 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Statistical Mechanics XIX, Plasma's Sound Propagation. Summer, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Thermodynamics, R. I. Lectures, 1961-1962 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Statistical Mechanics XX, Rockefeller Institute. [Dutch/English], 1961 February (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXI, Rockefeller Institute, 1962 January (Box 20, Folder 8)
    [Includes correspondence in Dutch].
  - Statistical Mechanics XXII, Rockefeller Institute, 1962 July (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Notes-Quantum Mechanics. Lectures, Rockefeller Institute, 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXIII, Rockefeller Institute, 1963 January (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXIV, Rockefeller Institute, 1965 January-February (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXV, Rockefeller Institute, 1966 February (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXVI, Fluctuation Theory, circa 1966 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Theory of Relativity-Notes III, 1967 January (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXVIII, Superfluids II. Rockefeller University, 1967 March (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXIX. Superfluids III. Lecture Notes, University of Colorado. Summer (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXII. Superfluids IV, circa 1968 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXVII, Mainly Kinetic Theory, Rockefeller University, 1969 May (Box 21, Folder 3)
    [Includes related, correspondence 1973-1974, 1980 in English and Dutch].
  - Statistical Mechanics XXX, Quantum Stat. Mech., Rocke. University, 1970 July (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Statistical Mechanics XXXI Random Processes and Fluctuation Theory, 1971 December (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Aanteekeininge II. Diraciana [English and Dutch], undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Anistrophe Media [in Dutch], undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Electricity and Magnetism [Dutch and English]. (1 of 2), undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Electricity and Magnetism [Dutch and English]. (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Equations-Untitled, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Hydrodynamics, [in Dutch], Utrecht?, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Kinetic Theory Problems (with? Robert L. Lewis Jr), undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Methode des Particuliere Soluties [Dutch and English], undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Notes of Work with Ehrenfest-Later Published in Nedrl. Academie [in Dutch] (1 of 2), undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Notes of Work with Ehrenfest-Later Published in Nedrl. Academie [in Dutch] (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Quantum Mechanics (1 of 2), undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Quantum Mechanics (2 of 2), undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Randwaardop. by Particle Diff. Verg I, Elliptisch Type (In Dutch), undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Randwaard. Problemen by Particle Diff. Verg. II Hyperbolische Type (in Dutch), undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Statistical Mechanics II (in Dutch), undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Statistical Mechanics III (in Dutch), undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Statistische Mecanica, College Ehrsnfest, (in Dutch), undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Statistische Mecanica, G.E.U. I, College Ehrenfest. [in Dutch], undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Statistische Mecanica, G.E.U. II, [in Dutch], undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Statistische Mecanica, G.E.U. III, [in Dutch], undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Theorie der Verrauelingen [in Dutch], undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Thermodynamics, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Notebook-Untitled, Notes state 'Don't know the writing, Notebook bought in Dan Bosch... ', undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Untitled-Russian/English Translation and Grammar Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Reprints of Contemporary Physicists, 1934-1966, undated; 7; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  Includes lecture notes and articles by Hans Bethe, Richard Feynman, Enrico Fermi and J. Robert Oppenheimer.
  - "Ersetzung der Hypothese vom unmechanischen Zwang durch eine Forderung bezüglich des innern Verhaltens jedes einzelnen Electrons" (with S. Goudsmit), Die Naturwissenschaften, [in German] vol. 13, 953-954, 1925 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Opmerking over de Spectra van Waterstof in Helium" (with S. Goudsmit), Physica [in Dutch], vol. 5, 266-270, 1925 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Over een Steelling van Lorentz en Haar Uitbreiding voor Meerdimensionale Ruimten, Physica [in Dutch], vol. 5, 423-428, 1925 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Die Kopplungsmöglichkeiten der Quantenvektoren im Atom" (with S. Goudsmit) [in German] vol. 35, 618-625, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "On the Connection of Different Methods of Solution of the Wave Equation in Multi-dimensional Spaces" (with P. Ehrenfest) Proceedings Royal Academy Amsterdam, vol. 29, 1280-1285, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Over het Roteerende Electron en de Structuur der Spectra" (with S. Goudsmit), Physica [in Dutch], vol 6, 273-290, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "Zum Einsteinschen "Miischungsparaciodoxon" (with P. Ehrenfest). Zeitschrift für Physik [in German] vol. 41, 24-26, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "A Problem in Brownian Motion" (with S. Goudsmit), Physical Review, vol. 34, 145-151, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "On the Wentzel-Brillouin-Kramers Approximate Solution of the Wave Equation" (with L. A. Young), Physical Review, vol. 36, 1154-1167, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "The Value of e/m by Deflection Experiments" (with L. A. Young), Physical Review, vol. 36, 1721-1727, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "Brownian Motion of Strings and Elastic Rods" (with G. A. van Lear), Physical Review, vol. 38, 1583-1598, 1931 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Transport Phenomena in Einstein-Bose and Fermi-Dirac Gases" (with E. A. Uehling) Physical Review, vol. 43, 552-561, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "On the Recombination of Electrons and Positrons" (with Enrico Fermi), Physical Review, vol. 44, 510-511, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "Disintegration of Li/6 by Protons and Deutrons" (with Ta You Wu), Physical Review, vol. 45, 553-554, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "Spontaneous Disintegration of Proton or Neutron According to the Fermi Theory" (with H. C. Wolfe). Physical Review, vol. 46, 237, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "The Probability of Position in a Canonical Ensemble", Journal of Mathematics and Physics, (M.I.T.) vol. 14, 10-16, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - "Statistical Energy Distribution for a Small Number of Particles" (with S. Goudsmlt). Pieter Zeeman Jubilee Volume, The Hague, Nijhoff, 201-211, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - "On the Fermi Theory of B-Radioactivity" (with E. J. Konopinski), Physical Review, vol. 48, 7-12, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - "Higher Order Derivatives in the Interaction "Ansatz" of the Fermi Theory" (with E. J. Konopinski), Physical Review, vol. 48, 107-108, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - "The Formation of Electron-Positron Pairs by Internal Conversion of Radiation" (with M. E. Rose), Physical Review, vol. 48, 211-222, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "Emission of Gamma Radiation during the Beta Decay of Nuclei" (with J. K. Knipp), Physica. vol. 3, 425-439, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - "Some Kinetic Problems Regarding the Motion of Neutrons through Paraffine" (with L. S. Ornstein), Physica, vol. 4, 478-486, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - "Het Principe van Behoud van Energie". [in Dutch]. Gravenhage, Martinus Nijhoff, 1-16, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "On the Statistical Calculation of the Density of Energy Levels of the Nuclei" (with C. Van Lier), Physica, vol. 4, 531-542, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - "Note on the Law of Sargent" (with H. Kuiper), Physica, vol. 4, 601-605, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - "The Quantum Theory of Non-Ideal Gas. II, Behavior at Low Temperatures" (with E. Beth), Physica, vol. 4, 915-924, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - "Stability of Nuclear Isomers" (with M. H. Hebb), Physica, vol. 5, 605-608, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - "On the Theory of Cosmic-Ray Showers. I. The Furry Model and the Fluctuation Problem" (with A. Nordsieck and W. E. Lamb, Jr.), Physica, vol. 7, 344-360, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - "On the Fermi Theory of B-Radioactivity, II. The "Forbidden Spectra" (with E. J. Konopinski). Physical Review, vol. 60, 308-320, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - "On the Theory of Cosmic-Ray Showers. Further Contributions to the Fluctuation Problem" (with W. T. Scott), Physical Review, vol. 62, 497-508, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - "On the Transport Phenomena in Rarified Gas-Monograph" (with C. S. Wang Chang), University of Michigan, 1-22, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - "Difraction of Shock Waves Around Various Obstacles", Engineering Research Institute, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Monograph (1-6) with photographic examples (1-73), 1950 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - "On Field Theories with Non-Localized Action" (with A. Pais), Physical Review, vol. 79, 145-165, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - "On the Directional Correlation of Successive Nuclear Radiations" (with D. L. Falkoff), Physical Review, vol 79, 323-333, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - "On the Beta-Gamma-Angular Correlation" (with D. L. Falkoff), Physical Review, vol. 79, 334-340, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - "On the Notion of Pressure in a Canonical Ensemble" (with R. J. Riddell Jr.), Journal of Chemical Physics, vol. 18, 1066-1069, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - "Transport Phenomena in Polvatomic Gases-Monograph" (with C. S. Wang Chang), University of Michigan, 1-46, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - "Is There a Neutral u-Meson"? (with C. S. Wang Chang), Physical Review, vol. 85, 684, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - "On the Propagation of Sound in Monatomic Gases-Monograph" (with C. S. Wang Chang), University of Michigan, 1-52, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - "The Heat Transport Between Parallel Plates As Functions of the Knudson Number-" Monograph (with C. S. Wang Chang), University of Michigan, 1-32, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - "On the Theory of the Vrial Development of the Equation of State of Monoatomic Gases" (with R. J. Riddell Jr.), Journal of Chemical Physics. vol. 21, 2056-2064, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - "Transport Verschijnselen in Meer-Atomige Gassen, Natuurkunde" [in Dutch], 329-336, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "Combinatorial Problems in the Theory of Graphs. I." (with G. W. Ford), Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. vol. 42, 122-128, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Combinatorial Problems in the Theory of Graphs. II. " (with G. W. Ford and R. Z. Norman), Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, vol. 42, 203-208, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "On the Behavior of Gas Near a Wall-Monograph" (with C. S. Wang Chang), University of Michigan, 1-32, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Reminiscences of Professor Paul Ehrenfest", American Journal of Physics, vol. 24, no. 6, 431-433, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "The Symmetry in Time and Other Basic Symmetry Laws of Nature", Michigan Alumnus Quarterly Review, vol. LXIII, No. 10, 50-55, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "Some Fundamental Problems in Statistical Physics", Proceedings of the International Congress of Mathematicians, 256-267, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "On the Quantum Theory of the Third Virial Coefficient" (with A Pals), Physical Review, vol. 116, 250-269, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - "Some Recent Progress in Statistical Mechanics", Physics Today, vol. 13, no. 7, 16-21, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "Part B, the Theory of Linear Graphs with Applications to the Theory of Virial Development the Properties of Values" (with G. W. Ford), Studies in Statistical Mechanics, vol. 1, 1-211, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion of the Distribution Functions" (with M. Kac and P. C. Hemmer), Journal of Mathematical Physics, vol. 4, 229-247, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "Is There an Arrow in Time"? Rockefeller Institute Review, vol. 1, no. 2, 10-15, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - "Alte und Neue fragen der Statistischen Mechanik", Physikertagung [in English], 1-19, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - "Part B. A Critical Study of Some Theories of the Liquid State including a Comparison with Experiment", (by J. M. H. Leveit And E. G. D. Cohen), J. de Boer and G. E. Uhlenbeck, editors, North Holland Publishing Co. 1-239, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - "Statistical Mechanics of Equilibrium and Non-equilibrium. On Critical Phenomena in a van der Waals Gas" (with P. C. Hemmer), Proceedings of the International Symposium on Statistical Mechanics of Thermodynamics, Aachen, 241-252, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Part C. The Heat Conductivity and Viscosity of Polyatomic Gases" (with C. S. Wang Chang and J. de Boer), Studies in Statistical Mechanics, vol. II, 243-268, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. III. Discussion of the Critical Region" (with P. C. Hemmer and M. Kac), Journal of Mathematical Physics, vol. 5, 60-74, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - "van der Waals Revisited" [in Dutch], North Holland Publishing Co., 1-16, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - "Structure of Statistical Mechanics", Proceedings of the 1966 Midwest Conference on Theoretical Physics, Indiana University, 1-12 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - "Propagation of Sound in Monatomic Gases" (with J. Foch), Physical Review Letters. vol. 19, 1025-1027, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - "Gibt Es eine Richtung im Aglauf der Zeit"? Umschau Verlag, Frankfurt [in German], Heft 8, 237-241, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - "Teaching of Physics of Fluids in U.S. Colleges and Universities" (with Raymond J. Emerich and Howard A. Snyder), American Journal of Physics, vol. 36, no. 10, 886-895 1968) (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - "Thermodynamic Equilibrium of Rotating Superfluids" (with S. Putterman), Physics of Fluids, vol. 12. 2229-2236, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - "Contributions to Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics. I. Theory of Hydrodynamical Fluctuations" (with R. F. Fox), Physics of Fluids, vol. 13, 1893-1902, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - "Contributions to Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics. II. Fluctuation Theory for the Bolzmann Equation" (with R. F. Fox), Physics of Fluids, vol. 13, 2881-2890, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 25)